A Guide to the Papers of Epes Sargent
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Epes Sargent 1839-1880
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7920, -a, -b
This collection consists of 19 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
7920 was purchased from Robert K. Black, 1965 March 15; 7920-a was a gift of Clifton Waller Barrett, 1963 December 16; 7920-b was purchased from Lawrence B. Romains, 1951 April 24.
Scope and Content Information
The papers contain an autograph draft and corrected manuscript of "The London Belle, Or Events of a Season," a manuscript poem, and a quotation.
Most of the letters pertain to Sargent's work as editor of the Boston Daily Evening Transcript. He regrets the lack of an esprit de corps among editors, praises William A. Wheeler's new edition of Webster's Dictionary and Robert Dale Owen's book on slavery. Spiritualism is a frequent topic and he refers to John Tyndall's attack on it and his own defense.
With these is a letter from Sir Thomas Noon Talfourd to Wiley, Long and Putnam discussing the potential for publishing Sargent's play "Velasco" in England and an engraving of Sargent.
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - The London belle, or, Events of a Season 1847, AMs, 85 p.
    7920-b
  - The London belle, or, Events of a Season [1847], AMs, 61 p.
    Corrected copy. 7920-b
  - "We will not deplore them" 1857 Aug 10, AMsS, poem, 1 p.
    7920-a
  - "Not by night" 1862 Dec 23, AMsS, poem, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Sir Thomas Noon Talfourd to Wiley & Putnam 1839 Jan 24, ALS, 3 p.
  - Epes Sargent to William A. Seaver 1852 Mar 17, ALS, 4 p.
  - Epes Sargent to George Pope Morris 1853 Jan 23, ALS, 2 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Edward L. Welles 1855 Apr 18, ALS, 1 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Fitz-Greene Halleck 1859 Oct 13, ALS, 2 pp.
    7920
  - Epes Sargent to Robert Dale Owen 1860 Oct 5
  - Epes Sargent to John Osborne Sargent 1863 Mar 25, ALS, 2 p.
  - Epes Sargent to William Adolphus Wheeler 1863 Apr 27, ALS, 3 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Robert Dale Owen 1864 Aug 26, ALS, 1 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Bayard Taylor 1876 Jan 7, ALS, 8 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Mrs. Elizabeth Oaksmith 1876 May 17, ALS, 3 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Miss Harriet Jacobsen 1877 Mar 22, ALS, 2 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Maturin Murray Ballou 1880 May 17, ALS, 1 p.
  - Epes Sargent to Mrs. Elizabeth Oaksmith n.d., ALS, 1 p.
- Head and shoulders engraving of Epes Sargent n.d.